Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 12.01.22 21:47:55
[woman speaking in Spanish]
你最好忘记他们 什么都没看见
把包扔掉 太显眼了 会引人注意的
[siren blaring]
[screaming]
[gunshot]
[greeting]
美丽的美国
[talks in Russian]
弗里德曼参议员 你这几个月来
Now, Senator Friedman, you have been a harsh critic...
对总统的对俄政策批评很严厉
of the President in recent monthsabcover his treatment of Russia.
俄国重新崛起了 他们的总统明确表明了
Russia is back. Their presidentabchas stated unequivocally...
要把我们打回1985年的愿望
their desire to knock us back to 1985.
他们重新启动了核计划
They've reignited their nuclear program.
他们上周还在白令海派了3艘阿库拉型核潜艇
Just Iast week they dropped three Akulaabcclass subs in the Bering Sea.
我们在中东的短视
Our myopia over the Middle East...
使我们忽略了近在眼前的威胁
has caused us to miss the big bear that'sabcjust sitting in the middle of the room.
达登参议员 你在俄国有很多公司
Now, Senator Darden, you have numerousabcbusiness interests inside Russia.
你和弗里德曼参议员有同样的担心吗
Do you share Senator Friedman's fears here?
我在俄国的公司
My interests, as you call them, in Russia...
只是我国人民的贸易伙伴
are strictly as a trade partner forabcthe good people of my state.
弗里德曼参议员所鼓吹的威胁只是为了
All this saber rattling is basicallyabcSenator Friedman's attempt...
让他明年能得到拨款
to get his budget up for next year.
拜托 俄国目前在美国境内的密探
Oh, Please. Russia now has ten timesabcthe number of covert agents...
是冷战时期的十倍
within United States borders asabcit did during the Cold War.
你不知道吗 而且 你如果明智的话
What are we talking about? Besides,abcwouldn't it be wise for you...
这种形式下 不是应该放弃你在俄国的公司吗
to divest your interest of what youabchave in Russia at a time like this?
我的金融业务都是很透明的
I am very transparent about allabcof my financial transactions...
否则我也就不从事这些业务了
which is why, you know, that Iabcdid those things. Excuse me.
总统会认为 在目前担心是没有帮助的
The President would suggest that fearabcis not helpful right now, Senator...
任何政客显然都很擅长利用人们的担心
that fear is obviously a very big componentabcof any politician's toolbox...
但对于进步没什么帮助
but that it is not going to help toward progress.
他要走了
Leaving.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
[telephone rings]
喂
(Darden) Hello?
你还没有弄到钱
(man) You haven't accessed the money.
我们有些不安
Yeah, well, it's been a little warm around here.
我们有交易的 参议员 我们希望得到
We had a deal, Senator. We have expectations.
我不管你们想得到什么
I don't give a good goddamn about your expectations.
别再朝这里打电话
Don't call here again.
[phone off the hook]
这混蛋做了交易
Bastard's making a deal.
或是取消了一桩交易
Yeah, or blowing one off.
那我们怎么办
Where does that Ieave us?
达登刚联系了 好像他现在要走
Darden just made contact. ItabcIooks Iike he's moving now.
[elevator bell]
天 他倒下了 在大楼后面
Oh shit! He's down! He's down! Behind the building!
[sirens blaring]
这是国内案件
(Barton) This is a domestic case!
你们没有管辖权 无权到这里
You have no jurisdiction, authority, or right to be here.
我们跟踪他一个月了
We've been trailing this guy for the past month.
这是犯罪现场 不是恐怖袭击
This is a crime scene, not a goddamn terrorist attack!
你要等着
You're going to have to wait.
是吗 我等什么
Yeah? What am I supposed to wait for?
等他
[horn honking]
For him.
[mixed voices]
就是这里 长官
There you go, sir.
海兰局长 为什么中情局
Director Highland. Sir, why is the CIA--
我是韦弗特工 是
This is Agent Weaver. Yes, sir.
是
Yes, sir.
我们走
We're out!
谁的电话
Who the hell was that?
贝尔局长 他让我们撤出 不要问也不要说
Director Bell. He wants us out.abcNo questions and not a word.
你们一直跟踪他？
You guys were on the stakeout?
他和莫斯科一个人不时联络 有一个月了
Yes, sir. He's had contact with Moscowabcoff and on for a month now.
但他还没有别的
But he never went any further--
这我们知道 今晚发生了什么事
We know that. What happened here tonight?
有人从后面抓住他 在我们的盲点
Someone grabbed him from behind.abcRight in our blind spot.
发生的太快了
It all happened so goddamned fast.
盯着球
(man) Keep your eye on it!
[cheering]
打扰一下 你知道几点了吗
Excuse me? Do you know the time?
不知道 我没带表 抱歉
No, no. I don't have a watch. Sorry.
没事 我丈夫说他9点会来的
It's okay. Just, my husband said he'd be here by nine.
哦
Oh.
哪个是你儿子？
Which boy is yours?
德克尔 那个二垒手
Decker, the second baseman.
是啊 他打得很好
Oh, yeah. He's good.
投球很有力
Got a strong arm.
我叫莫莉
[chuckles] I'm Molly.
我叫保罗 你好
Paul. Hey.
哪个是你儿子？
Which one's yours?
再来一个
(coach) One more, guys!
我没有儿子
Oh, no, I don't, I don't have--
我住在附近
No, I Iive nearby here.
经常来看比赛
I come by just to see a game once in a while.
挺好的
That's really nice.
[dog barks]
你真是无忧无虑啊
Not a care in the world, huh?
天
Jeez!
从没想到我会让保罗・谢泼德森措手不及
I never thought I'd see the day when someoneabcgot the drop on Paul Shepherdson.
是啊 你是怎么进来的
Yeah, yeah. How did you get in here?
这是你我擅长的
It's what we do.
你可以打电话的
The phone rings, too, you know.
是卡修斯
It's Cassius.
他回来了
He's back.
汤姆
Tom.
卡修斯早就消失了
Cassius is Iong gone.
20多年没有他的消息了
He hasn't even been heard from in over 20 years.
但是达顿参议员不这么认为
Tell that to Senator Darden.
他正躺在小巷里 喉咙被割开了
He's Iying in an alley with his throat slit.
是别人模仿他的手法
Then it's a copycat.
每个人都这么说 除了一个人
That's what everyone is saying. Well, almost everyone.
汤姆 我对他太了解了
Tom, there was a point where I knewabcthis man better than myself.
卡修斯死了
Cassius is dead.
保罗 这一次我觉得你错了
For once, Paul, I think you're wrong.
[mixed voices]
欢迎回来 先生
(agent) Welcome back, sir.
各位
Gentlemen.
保罗 这是罗杰・贝尔局长
Paul, this is Director Roger Bell.
谢泼德森先生
Mr. Shepherdson.
联邦调查局的？
The FBI?
中情局变了 朋友
Bureaucracy has changed, my friend.
我们需要和联邦调查局合作
We have to share the burden now.
大家知道 保罗曾经负责
As you know, Paul was responsible...
追查“卡修斯七人组”
for tracking down the Cassius Seven...
这是我们为俄国杀手取的绰号
The Soviet assassins we code-named...
借用杀害凯撒的七位古罗马元老院议员
for the Roman senators who killed Julius Caesar.
据我所知 他们都被你抓住了 只除了一个人
And you caught them all but one,abcfrom what I understand.
没抓到卡修斯本人
Missed Cassius himself?
是的
That's right.
但这不是他干的 我肯定
But this is not his work. I'm sure of it.
我觉得是他
Oh, I think it is.
这人是谁
Who the hell is this?
这是我的人 本・吉尔利特工
This is one of my men. Agent Ben Geary.
在联邦调查局 他对卡修斯最了解
Probably knows more about yourabcassassin than anyone we've got.
中情局中也没人比他更了解
Or the CIA, for that matter.
保罗 我们希望你们两人合作
Paul, we'd like the two of you to work together.
是吗 告诉我 吉尔利
Is that so? So tell me, Geary...
柏林墙倒塌的时候 你在干什么
what were you doing when the wall came down?
我当时在电视上看
I was watching it on television.
在坐的和位也是一样
Just Iike everyone else in this room.
[laughter]
请调出案卷
Could you pull up the case file, please?
好的 看 下刀的地方
Okay, here is good. Notice how the cut starts...
在喉咙正中 然后向上割开
right in the center of the throat, moving upwards.
一般来说 下刀会在上面 向旁边割开
Typically, a cut starts high, moves lateral...
从左边划到右边
as the right-handed killer pullsabcthe knife from ear to ear.
卡修斯不是这样 他的刀口都是一样的
Not Cassius. His cuts were always exactly the same.
右手 向上 从喉咙中间下刀
Right-handed, but up, and startingabcin the middle of the neck.
我一直不明白为什么
I've never been able to figure out why.
仍然是别人模仿他的手法
Still, it's a copycat.
这就是所谓的专家？
This guy's the best you've got?
谢泼德森先生 我写过关于卡修斯的硕士论文
Mr. Shepherdson, I wrote myabcMaster's thesis on Cassius.
我跟踪调查过
And I have tracked down and interviewed...
目击他作案的极少数人中的每一位
every one of the few witnesses ofabchis crimes who are still alive.
我甚至设计过、并亲自走过他所有作案的
I've even re-created and personallyabcwalked the approaches and exits...
入口和出口 我了解这个人
of all his known kills step for step. I know this man.
我完全相信 这是卡修斯干的
And there is no doubt in my mind.abcThis is the work of Cassius.
你了解他？
You know him?
你是哈佛毕业的吧
Harvard, right?
是的
Yes, that's right.
你是驻土耳其大使馆一位外交官的儿子
And you were the son of a foreign attaché in Turkey.
我父亲在很多大使馆工作过
My father worked at embassies all over the world.
你怎么知道的
How do you know this?
我看过你的硕士论文
I read your thesis.
是吗
You did?
你当时一直想采访我
And I know you were trying for months to talk to me.
告诉你我为何拒绝了 因为你只是纸上谈兵
I'll tell you why I refused. Because youabchave never been on the ground.
因为你不了解他 也因为你只是图书管理员
Because you don't know him. Andabcbecause you're a Iibrarian.
谢泼德森先生
Mr. Shepherdson.
吉尔利 假如我真的错了 你查出来是他
Let's just say, Geary, that I'mabcwrong and you expose him.
你觉得下一步是什么
What do you think comes next?
你觉得他会追杀你？
You think maybe he's gonna come after you?
我正是为此而来
That is exactly why I'm here.
我要回去了
[exhales]
I'm going home.
希望不要再来烦我 好吗
And I'd like to be left alone. All right?
我们抓住了布鲁图
We've got Brutus.
什么
What?
伊戈尔・伊万诺维奇・科扎克 又名布鲁图
Igor Ivanovich Kozak, aka Brutus...
他还活着 正关在Brinkerman监狱
is alive and locked up in Brinkerman Penitentiary.
不可能 1989年他在萨尔兹堡把他杀了
That's impossible. He killed him in Salzburg in 1989.
我开枪打中他的胸部 他摔下了三层楼
I shot him in the chest. He fell three stories.
他活了下来
And survived.
你为何没告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
你当时想退休 保罗
You wanted to retire, Paul.
退休的人 有些事情就不能让他知道了
I'm afraid retirees Iose certain privileges.
既然这样
You know what?
这里没我什么事了
I'm done here, Tom.
给我接海兰
Get me Highland.
我知道你在 给我接海兰
Come on, I know you're there. Get me Highland.
您拨的号码是空号
(operator) Your call cannot be completed as dialed.
海兰局长想告诉你
Director Highland wants youabcto know he has a meeting...
他明早和总统会面
with the President tomorrow morning.
他说你知道这意味着什么
He said you'd know what that means.
早上好 两份 照旧
Good morning. Two regulars, please.
早上好 先生 马上就好
Good morning, sir. Coming right up.
特工不该养成任何习惯
Spooks aren't supposed to be creatures of habit.
当了领导就无所谓了
It's a Iuxury one can only afford when one is in charge.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常谢谢
(clerk) Thank you very much.
谢谢
Thanks.
我为你干了20年 汤姆
I gave you 20 years, Tom.
你保证过会让我过上正常生活
You promised me I could have a Iife.
我从来都不喜欢白宫的咖啡
I never cared much for the coffee at The White House.
可能是不习惯那里150年历史的瓷杯子
I think it's got something to doabcwith the 150-year-old china.
我是三任总统的中情局长
I've been Director through three presidents, Paul.
说实话 当初如果不是你
And Iet's face it. I wouldn't have gottenabcthe job in the first place...
打掉“卡修斯七人组”团伙 我也当不了局长
if you hadn't helped us with the Cassius Seven.
15分钟后 总统就会说 如果抓不住杀害达顿参议员的凶手
In 15 minutes, the President is gonna tellabcme I don't have this job anymore...
我就不再是局长了
if we can't nail the guy that killed Senator Darden.
不是卡修斯干的 汤姆
It's not Cassius, Tom.
你从未抓住他
You never caught him.
那是因为他死了
Because he's dead.
那你就证明
Then prove it.
[talking in French]
[woman speaking in French]
谢泼德森先生
Mr. Shepherdson?
保罗・谢泼德森
So, Paul Shepherdson.
在巴黎分部做分析师三年了
Been an analyst for the companyabchere in Paris for three years.
你找我什么事
What do you wanna see me about?
卡修斯七人组
The Cassius Seven.
我有了突破
I've had a breakthrough.
我可以帮你抓住他
I can take them down for you.
我会解决的 只要给我15分钟
(agent) I'll take care of it. Justabcgive me about 15 minutes.
喂
Oh, hey.
怎么样 怎么样
And? And, and, and, and?
不知道
I don't know.
贝尔局长在场？
Director Bell was there?
很多人都在场
Everyone was there.
天 我在这里干的时间比你还要长一年
Jesus! I've been at this place a year Ionger than you...
也从没见过局长本人
and I've never even seen the Director in person.
他们会派你执行任务 我能肯定
They're gonna put you in the field, man. I'm sure of it.
他们什么都没说
They haven't said anything, yet.
这个案子你一直都是对的
You were right about this thing the whole time, huh?
[telephone rings]
我是吉尔利特工 是
Agent Geary. Yes, sir.
是
Yes, sir.
是 我会去的
Yes, sir. I'll be there.
怎么样
And?
我要调查这案子了
I'm in.
真没想到
This is crazy.
我花了很长时间研究你对卡修斯的调查
'Cause I have spent so much timeabcstudying your work with Cassius.
感觉似乎了解你了
I feel Iike I know you.
你不了解
You don't.
对 我只是把我假设成你
Yeah. No, I just mean I-I, you know,abcI put myself in your shoes.
研究你会想什么
I just tried to think how you would think.
我有很多犯罪现场照片 不少照片中也有你
I've all of these crime scene photos.abcA lot of them you're in.
真该拿张照片让你签名的
Actually, I should probably get youabcto sign one of them. Right?
那肯定将是第一次签名
That would definitely be a first.
你91年去布达佩斯的时候 有没有注意到一种特定的模式？
When you were in Budapest in 91,abcdid you notice a specific pattern?
吉尔利特工
No, Agent Geary.
告诉我 你一个
Tell me why-why would a guy...
写过国际罪犯论文的人
who writes a thesis on an international spy...
为何加入联邦调查局 而不是中情局呢
join the Bureau and not Central Intelligence?
我认为卡修斯藏在美国
Well, I believed that Cassius was hiding in the U.S.
想想吧 苏联特工退休后去哪里最好呢
Think about it. What better placeabcfor a Soviet spook to retire?
你就凭此来选择你的事业？
You believe that enough to base a career on it?
对 可以这么说
Uh, yeah. You could say that.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
可以 只要你能闭嘴
If that means you'll stop talking, yeah.
他们为何不告诉你布鲁图没死？
Why didn't they tell you about Brutus?
既然你的职责就是抓住卡修斯七人组 他们为何不敢告诉你呢
If it was your job to catch the Cassius Seven,abcwhat were they scared you'd do?
怕我杀他
Kill him.
包里是什么
What's in the bag?
贿赂
Motivation.
你觉得他会说吗
You think he's gonna talk?
对我不会
Not to me.
[guard's indistinct talk]
他被检查过了
(guard) He's been cleared!
[clears throat]
我知道想了解卡修斯的事 就要找你
[talks in Russian]
你懂俄语？
You speak Russian, huh?
我在学校学过
I studied in school. Yes.
我给你来句俄语
Here's some Russian for you.
你妈是个婊子
我看资料 你和卡修斯共事过
I've read that you worked with Cassius.
那都是多年以前了
It's a different Iife ago.
你知道他藏在哪儿吗
Do you know where he's hiding?
你为何...
Why would you--
卡修斯还活着？
Is Cassius alive?
他杀了个参议员
He killed a Senator.
你是谁
Who are you?
我知道10年来你一直希望有个这种东西
I understand that you've been Iookingabcfor one of these for about 10 years.
[violin music playing]
[volume goes up]
给我
Give it to me.
告诉我一些卡修斯的情况 我就送给你
Tell me something that I don't knowabcabout Cassius and it is yours.
不想听听外面的世界吗
A chance to hear the outside world?
给我 你这混蛋
Give it to me, you son of a whore!
告诉我卡修斯的情况 他训练过你吗
Tell me something about Cassius. Did he train you?
他什么模样
What does he look like?
[music continues]
[music stops]
你就在寂静中过一辈子吧
I guess you can spend the rest of your Iife in silence.
狱警
Guard?
等等
[shouts] Wait!
好吧
Okay.
他是一个出名的战士
He made his name as a soldier.
但他并没有选择轻松的上学
But rather than take the easyabcroute through the academia...
而是练就了其它的本事
he honed other skills.
还训练了你？
And he trained you?
我们都是他训练的 以他的方式
He trained us all ...his way.
他只想要最棒的
He only wanted the best.
为此他想看到证明
For that he wanted proof.
上面是你们要杀的人
我们只有6个活了下来
Only six of us survived.
再加上他 就成为你们所说的“卡修斯七人组”
And together we became your Cassius Seven.
然后你再没见过他？
And you never saw him again?
没有
No.
我们通过通常渠道 从他那里得到暗杀目标
We got our targets from himabcthrough the usual channels.
但怎么下手都是他计划的
But he planned the kills.
他的情报总是最精确的
His intel was always the best.
对于何时动手 他的直觉总是最敏锐的
His instinct for when to strike, always sharpest.
他为何失踪了
What happened to him?
他犯了错误
He made mistake.
他违反了规矩
He lived outside parameters.
什么规矩
What kind of parameters?
杀手的规矩
Parameters of an assassin.
你把他怎么样了
What did you do to him?
把收音机给他
Give him the radio.
不 我想问清楚...
No, no. I wanna hear specifically--
我让你把收音机给他
I said give him the radio!
照做 给他
Just do it! Give it to him.
我们走
AII right. Let's go.
走
Come on!
[music playing]
狱警
Guard.
[sighs]
[gate opens and closes]
刚才怎么回事
What the hell was that?
为什么不让我问完
Why didn't you Iet me finish my Iine of questioning?
因为他在撒谎
Because he was Iying.
我以前杀他是有原因的
I tried to kill him once for a reason.
但是金属丝完全符合
Yeah, but the wire makes perfect sense.
恰好说明为何刀口总是从中间开始
It explains why the cuts alwaysabcstart from the middle...
然后向上划开 这就说明了一切
and then work their way up. This opens up everything.
我明早要去局里
I gotta get in there early tomorrow morning...
把刀口和其它的金属丝杀人案比较一下
and compare the cuts with otherabcwire killings in Europe.
[indistinct talk over P.A.]
[music from radio]
[sighs]
[buzzer]
[gate closes]
[footsteps]
[music stops]
[grunts]
[panting]
什么情况
What do we got?
抽筋 吐血
Cramping and vomiting blood.
带他去三号急诊室
Okay, get him into three.
[groaning]
解开他
Somebody get these restraints off!
我来
Excuse me.
给我个碗 碗
Can I get a bowl? Bowl, please!
来了
Got it.
电池
Batteries.
别过来
Stay back!
叫保安
(doctor) All right, get me security!
[people shouting]
你咽了电池吧
(Paul) You swallowed the batteries, didn't you?
从医院逃走 比从监狱逃走容易
Easier to escape from a hospital than a prison.
[shooting]
日内瓦
Geneva.
你当时在吧
You were there, weren't you?
我不知道...
I know nothing about--
你当时在 是你干的
You were there. It was you.
我从未在日内瓦杀过人
I never killed anyone in Geneva.
你撒谎
You are a Iiar.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是在萨尔兹堡对你开枪的人
I'm the one who shot you in Salzburg.
也是我在莫斯科训练的你
I'm also the one who trained you in Moscow.
卡修斯？
Cassius?
我在事后 才知道日内瓦的事
I never... I never knew aboutabcGeneva until after the fact.
他们派和你没关系的人干的
They brought in someone with-with no ties to you.
其他人也这么说
Yeah, the others said that, too.
他们说过是个“黑高加索”的人吗
Did they tell you it was someoneabcfrom the Black Caucasus?
好像是个当兵的
A soldier, I think.
我们一起能找到他
We could find him together.
咱俩是一个地方出来的
We are from the same place.
我一辈子都崇拜你
I've Iooked up to you my whole Iife.
[no audible dialog]
[bells tolling]
[horn honking]
[woman screaming]
[telephone ringing]
总是那么准时
[talking in Russian]
那美国人死了
他们给你取了个名字
我知道 他们叫我卡修斯
[telephone ringing]
我是吉尔利特工
(Geary) Agent Geary.
吉尔利特工 我们要见个面
(Paul) Agent Geary. We need to meet.
[voices whispering]
噢
Oh.
你需要放弃调查
You need to drop this investigation.
我为何要放弃
How exactly am I supposed to drop it?
卡修斯不在乎杀任何人
Cassius doesn't care who he has to eliminate.
如果他来杀我 我有所准备 但你没有
If he comes after me, I'm prepared. Not you.
你有老婆 有两个孩子
You've got a wife. You have two kids.
他们知道我做的事是很重要的
Yeah. I think they understandabcwhat I'm doing is important.
你有没有想过 如果你找到他 你会干什么吗
Have you thought about what you'reabcgonna do if you find him?
我一直都在想
That is all I think about.
现在成为现实了 我想知道更多
And now that it's real, I want it more.
我想了解他 我想理解他
I want to know him. I want to understand him.
然后呢
And then?
然后我想把他永远抓起来
And then I wanna put him away, for good.
哇 这些是什么
(Oliver) Whoa. What is all this shit?
这是调查
It's research.
调查
Research.
人民...
Volks-Volkskrant-Volks.
人民报 是荷兰的一份日报
De Volkskrant. It's a daily newspaper in Holland.
第三版有个金属丝杀人案的报道
The third page there's a story about a wire killing.
发生在苏联第一次公开选举之前
Ten days before the Soviets heldabctheir first open election.
卡修斯干的？
Cassius?
我觉得是
Yeah. I think so.
你一定要推荐我参与这个案子
You've gotta put in a word to get me on this case.
我整天研究垃圾金融案 我说真的
Please. I'm up to my ass in bankingabcbullshit. I'm serious.
[telephone rings]
我是吉尔利特工
Agent Geary.
在哪儿
Where?
[muffled voices]
[telephone rings]
等你拍完尸体照片
Once you're done getting shots of the body...
再拍拍伤口类型 脖子处的伤口要特写
really get the cut patterns. Iabcwant close-ups of the neck.
[distant siren blaring]
然后他到了这里？
And then he came in here?
是的
Yes, sir.
[no audible dialog]
嗨 保罗
Hey, Paul.
吉尔利特工 你有什么发现？再见
Agent Geary. What do you got? See you Iater.
布鲁特看来吞了我们给他的收音机的电池
Apparently Brutus swallowed the batteriesabcfrom the radio that we gave him.
估计他打了几个电话 找个藏身处
I'm guessing he put out some calls.abcFound a place to Iay Iow.
被卡修斯得到消息
Word got back to Cassius.
他不想留下后患
He's never one to allow Ioose ends.
后患 你是指他和我们谈过
Loose ends, meaning he spoke to us.
应该是吧
Probably. Yeah.
我们要收集医院内的
Well, we should get all the phone records...
所有手机通话记录
of every cell phone hospital extension here.
好
AII right. Okay.
我一直有个假设
You know, I always had this theory...
卡修斯会回到他的犯罪现场
that Cassius would return to the scene of his crimes.
看着调查案子的人
Watch his investigators.
你觉得他那么虚荣？
You think he's that vain?
我觉得一部分是虚荣
Well, I think that some of it's vanity.
也是为了看看他的对手是谁
Some of it is he wants to see what he's up against.
看见后面那个穿褐色夹克的人吗
You see that guy in the back? Brown jacket.
俄国品牌的夹克
Coat's Russian made.
喂 先生 先生
Excuse me, sir? Sir?
靠 让开
(Geary) Shit! Move!
[panting]
好  我们分头去追
AII right. Why don't we split up?
好
Yeah.
你去那里
You go that way.
[exhales]
[clanking]
我没有发现
I've got nothing.
我也没有 报告联邦调查局
Yeah, me neither. Let the Bureau know.
他穿着褐色小山羊皮夹克
He's wearing a brown suede jacket.
金发 平头
Sandy blond hair, close cropped.
不 他不是卡修斯
No. That wasn't him.
他个子不高
He was too tall.
气质 体型 年龄 太多地方不符合
Too military. Wrong build. Too young.abcA million reasons. It wasn't him.
那我们为何追他
What the hell were we doing chasing this guy?
他逃跑 我估计他肯定有什么罪名
He ran. I figured he'd be arrested for something.
你饿了吗
You hungry?
嗨 保罗 这是我老婆 娜塔莉
Hey, Paul. This is my wife, Natalie.
你好 谢泼德森先生
Hello, Mr. Shepherdson.
叫我保罗
Hey. Paul.
保罗
Paul.
我好久没去别人家吃过饭了
It's been a Iong time since I wentabcto someone's house for dinner.
不懂得什么礼节
I, uh, I never Iearned how to do it right.
很简单 你只要微笑着点头 说饭菜很好吃
Well, it's easy. You just smile andabcnod and tell me how good it is.
是
Yes, ma'am.
"是"你听见了吗
Ma'am? Did you hear that?
阁下这边请
Well, right this way, sir.
欢迎光临寒舍
Let me welcome you to our humble commode.
[kid humming]
帮我准备晚饭吧
Wanna help me get dinner ready?
准备晚饭
Dinner ready?
我帮不了什么忙 对不起
I'm not gonna be much help. I'm sorry.
只要把爸爸从后院挪到厨房里
It's easy. Just move the dad fromabcthe backyard to the kitchen.
这是你爸爸？我看看
That's your dad? Let's see.
喂 保罗 见见这个小家伙
Hey, Paul. Come meet this Iittle guy.
[chuckles]
他叫尼古拉斯
It's Nicholas.
哇
Wow.
长得很像你
Yeah. Looks Iike you.
不像
No.
鼻子随你
Yeah. Got your nose.
都说他像我爸爸
Everyone says he Iooks Iike my dad.
这话我爱听 因为他10年前去世了
Which is nice 'cause we Iost him Iike ten years ago.
对不起
Yeah, I'm sorry.
没关系
No, no, it's fine.
他肯定是你儿子
He's definitely your kid.
你有孩子吗 保罗？
Do you have any children, Paul?
我没有
No. No, I don't.
你喝酒吗
Do you want a drink?
好
Yeah.
孩子 来
Yeah, sweetie. Come on.
托着他的头
You got his head?
来 露西 我们上楼
Come on, Lucy. Let's go set up, sweetie.
保罗 你喝什么
Paul, what are you Iooking for?
伏特加马提尼
Vodka martini?
好的
Sure.
不加冰 加一片洋葱
Dry. With, uh, an onion if you've got it.
知道吗
You know what?
你调查卡修斯的时间太长了
I think you've been chasing Cassius a Iittle too Iong.
都喜欢他的酒了
That's his drink.
都尽量了解他
Yeah. Well, trying to get into his head...
也染上了一些他的习惯
I guess I picked up some of his habits.
尽然这样 我和你一起喝
You know what? In that case, I'm gonna join you.
孩子们终于睡下了
The kids are down. Finally.
我知道你会觉得荒唐
Now, I know you're gonna say this is weird...
但我感觉和卡修斯心理相通
but I feel a connection with him. I do. With Cassius.
他不是那种你能与之沟通的人
He's not the kind of guy that you can connect to.
如果不算相通 也算是对他非常的尊敬
Well, sure. If not a connection, thenabca tremendous amount of respect.
我要向你证明
AII right. Let's just set the record straight now.
他不值得你任何的尊敬和钦佩
He's not worthy of your respect or admiration.
他是个冷血杀手
He's a cold-blooded ki//er.
不像你有个家庭
He doesn't have a family like you.
不像你有个老婆
He doesn't have a wife Iike yours.
他的一生一文不值
His Iife meant nothing.
他做过唯一一件好事就是消失
The only good thing he everabcdid was disappear. All right?
他在某些方面非常优秀
You don't think there's somethingabcto be respected in the fact that...
你不觉得值得尊敬吗
he is the best at something?
对这样的禽兽 我没有一点尊敬
Respect is the Iast thing I haveabcfor an animal Iike him. Okay?
没错 可是...
Yeah. But--
等一下 我去撒尿
Hold that thought. I'm gonna take a piss.
本
Ben?
我只是说了大实话
I'm just stating the facts.
他满脑子都是他
Paul, he's obsessed.
是啊
Yeah, I know.
自从我认识他就是这样
And he has been ever since I've known him.
卡修斯
Cassius.
还有你
And you!
我希望你这个案子早点结束
You know, I'm-I'm just ready for it to be over.
你丈夫招惹了一个
Your husband is messing with a creature...
他自以为了解的人
he thinks he understands, but he doesn't.
他之所以还没对你丈夫下手
He's allowed your husband...
是因为他构不成太大威胁
to Iive this Iong because he wasn't much of a threat.
你这话什么意思
What do you mean, allowed him to Iive?
你觉得他知道我丈夫是谁？
Do you think he knows who my husband is?
他肯定知道
I'm sure he does.
你真的看过我的论文？
You really read my thesis?
是的 我看过你的论文
Yes. Yes, I read your thesis.
是吗
Yeah?
怎么样
And?
好吧 我觉得...
AII right. I think...
你漏了一个重要的问题
that you missed an essential question.
什么问题
Okay. What's that?
你准确描述了卡修斯的方式和地点
You pinpointed the wheres and the hows of Cassius...
但你从没问为什么
but you never ask the question why.
为什么他杀的人越来越没有规律？
Why were his targets increasingly more random?
他为何失踪
Why did he disappear?
等你明白了这些问题
When you can answer those whys...
你才能了解他
then you'll know him.
替我再次谢谢娜塔莉
Thank Natalie again, will you?
我们检查了医院的电话
Oh, we checked the calls from the hospital.
怎么样
Yeah?
没有发现
Nothing.
太遗憾了
Tch. Too bad.
是啊
Yeah.
问题是...
See, you know the thing that--
我有一点不明白
Okay, here's what I don't understand.
卡修斯怎么知道会把布鲁图转移到医院
How did Cassius know that theyabcmoved Brutus to a hospital...
而不是在监狱里治疗呢
instead of just working on him at the prison?
俄国人应该是买通了监狱里的人
The Russians probably paid somebody off in the prison.
希望他死 杀人灭口
They'd want him dead just to shut him up.
对 对
Right. Right.
再见 吉尔利
Good night, Geary.
[dog barking]
[helicopter flying by]
各位
Gentlemen?
你们认识马丁・米勒吧
I think you guys know Martin Miller.
他是研究国内俄国间谍的专家
He's our Chief Analyst on domestic Russian ops.
开始吧 马丁
Go ahead, Marty.
大约半年前 两个BP特工被杀 卡车被抢
Almost six months ago, two B.P agentsabcwere murdered and their truck stolen.
这辆卡车一周后出现在TUS附近 没留下蛛丝马迹
The truck was located a week later inabca parking lot near TUS wiped clean.
这些人是聪明人 停车的地方离摄像头很远
Now, these guys were smart. They parkedabcfar enough away from the cameras...
辨别不出面容
that we couldn't get any facial recognition.
当地警方和边境巡逻队估计他们是墨西哥人
Local cops and Border Patrolabcassumed they were Mexican.
后来我们发现这个
Then we found this.
警车上的摄像头？
A camera in a squad car.
是的 幸运的是 图森警方在一些警车上
That's right. Luckily, Tucson police were testing...
测试高分辨率摄像头
high-resolution cameras in a few cars.
都是俄国人 都是已知的特工
All Russian. All known operatives.
现在都在美国
AII now in the United States.
这是那个穿俄国夹克的人
(Geary) There's the guy with the Russian jacket.
是的 还有更好的
That's right. And it gets better.
等一下 等一下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Wait.
这混蛋
Son-of-a-bitch.
巴兹洛斯基
Bozlovski.
是的 约翰・巴兹洛斯基
That's right. Johann Bozlovski.
前苏联特种部队和情报局特工
Former Spetsnaz and KGB.
1990年 波兹洛斯基和他在"黑高加索"的第十山地旅
In 1990, Bozlovski and his 10th MountainabcBrigade in the Black Caucasus...
进入华沙 处决了第三世界结盟运动的盟友
went into Warsaw and executed knownabcallies of the solidarity movement.
在柏林墙倒塌后
I Iooked for him for a year...
我找了他一年
after the wall came down.
他突然失踪了
He just, just vanished.
就像卡修斯
Like Cassius.
你觉得呢 保罗
What are you thinking, Paul?
一个已知的苏联杀手
We have a known Soviet hit man.
失踪后进入利比亚或阿富汗
Disappears into Libya or Afghanistan.
与此同时 我们的情报显示卡修斯也是这样
Same time our intel tells us Cassius does the same.
20年后 他露面了
Twenty years Iater, he shows up.
美国参议员的喉咙被割开了
United States Senator gets his throat slit.
我觉得不太可能
[exhales] I-I don't know.
波兹洛斯基是特种部队的
I mean, Bozlovski's Spetsnaz.
太显眼了
And... he's so visible.
也许正是他们的意图所在
Well, yeah. Maybe that's what they wanted.
派个显眼的人
And wouldn't a more visible alter ego...
吸引我们的注意力 就会忽略别的
just muddy up the waters for everyone chasing him?
我们怎么确定波兹洛斯基1990年在华沙？
How did we know Boz was in Warsaw in 1990?
怎么能确定？
How did we know that?
只是因为俄国人是这么说的
Because the Russians told us so!
在柏林墙倒塌前 苏联的假情报
Soviet disinformation was theabcbiggest weapon they had...
是他们最大的武器
before the wall came down.
没错
That's true.
[exhales]
是啊
Yeah.
有可能是波兹洛斯基
Bozlovski makes sense.
就是他
It's him. He's the one.
你们需要我们干什么
What do you guys need from us?
什么都不要干 如果他知道我们盯上了他
Nothing. Nothing. He'll disappear again...
他会再次消失的
if he knows we're onto him.
[alarm sounding]
这是什么地方
What is this place?
[knocks]
[talks in Russian]
[clattering]
[woman arguing]
安波
Amber.
安波？
Amber?
那个人走私俄国货
Yeah, that guy deals in Russian goods.
任何来自俄国的东西
Anything from the homeland.
拐入河边
Turn down by the river.
[dog barking]
打扰一下
我来找安波
别干那事 把床单都弄坏了
在河边
谢谢
[man shouting]
安波是个妓女？
Amber's a prostitute?
如果俄国人用他们的女人而不是导弹做武器
If the Russians used their women instead of missiles...
早就把我们征服了
we'd all be wearing furry hats right now.
[man and woman arguing]
[baby crying]
这是美最脏的河流 你知道吗
This is the dirtiest river in the U.S. Did you know that?
就在我们的国会大厦旁
Right here in our nation's capitol.
这是停房车的好地方
Nice place to park your house.
安波
Amber?
[loud rock music]
[talks in Russian]
[loud music]
别跑
No, no.
[shouting]
闭嘴
Shut up!
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna-- I'm not gonna hurt you!
[talks in Russian]
波兹洛斯基 他在哪儿
Bozlovski. Bozlovski. Where is he?
[shouting in Russian]
波兹洛斯基在哪儿
Where is Bozlovski?
我不知道你说的是谁
I don't know who you're talking about!
[loud rock music]
[shouts in Russian]
[screaming]
闭嘴
Shut up!
[talks in Russian]
[lowers music]
[Amber shouting]
波兹洛斯基在哪儿
Where is Bozlovski?
我会把你杀死在这里
I will kill you here...
扔到河里冲走 我对天发誓
and Iet you float away. I swear to God.
求你不要
Please. Please don't.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
求你了 我不知道
I am begging you. I don't know.
胡说 你是胡说
Bullshit. That is bullshit.
保罗 是我们闯入她的家
Paul, we broke into her place! Okay?
闭嘴回到车上
Go back to the car and shut up!
他在哪儿
Where is he?
求你了
Please.
保罗 让我和她谈谈
Paul, Iet me talk to her!
求你了
Please.
[groans]
求你了 我什么都不知道
Please, I don't know anything.
算你命大
You're a very Iucky girl.
来
Come.
[talking in Russian]
你不会是让她看了你孩子的照片吧
You didn't really show her picturesabcof your kids, did you?
我在基地学过一些招数
You know, they teach you a couple tricks at Quantico.
噢 基地 唱红脸 唱白脸
Oh, Quantico. Good cop, bad cop.
为了沟通
Making a connection.
噢 很不错
Oh! Very nice.
是吗
Yeah?
[talking in Russian]
我认识你们要找的人
I, uh, I know-- I know this man you're Iooking for.
我可以带你们去
Okay? You-you can follow me there.
你是谁
Who are you?
她哥哥
Her brother.
哦
Oh.
我带你们去找波兹洛斯基
Look, I take you to where Bozlovski is.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
里奥
Leo.
里奥 把手机给我
Leo. Leo, give me your phone.
把手机给我
Give me your phone.
好的
There you go.
里奥 你没给别人打电话说你要来吧
Now, Leo, you didn't call anyone andabctell them we were coming, did you?
没有 我发誓
No. No, no. No, I swear.
如果你耍什么花样 我会让她吃两颗枪子
Now, if anything goes wrong, Leo, I'mabcputting two bullets in her head...
把尸体扔到河里 然后再去找你
and I'm dumping her in the river.abcThen I'm coming for you.
好的
Okay.
你要对她开枪？
You're gonna shoot her in the head?
只是为了沟通
Just making a connection.
好 就是这里
Okay. This is the place.
好 波兹洛斯基就在里面
Okay, Bozlovski, he's in there.
别走 过来
No, no, no. No, no, come on.
里奥 喂
Leo! Hey.
你有几个妓女？
How many girls you got?
告诉我 5个？10个？
Come on, tell me. Five? Ten?
15个？告诉我
Fifteen? Talk to me. Huh?
两个
Two.
什么
What?
-两个 -两个
Two.
好
AII right.
你带我找到波兹洛斯基
You get me to Bozlovski...
就能继续你的生意
you keep your business...
我也假装没见过你 好吗
and we never met. AII right?
你呼叫后援 或者用你在基地学到的招数
You. Call for backup, or whateverabcthey told you to do at Quantico.
守在门口 不要离开
You stay there by the door. You don't Ieave.
去吧
Go.
他也来吗
He comes, too?
不 他留在门口 走吧
No, no, he stays at the door. Go on.
很好 我最擅长的就是看门了
Perfect. Because I was first inabcmy class in door watching.
[talking in Russian]
听说你在调查我
I hear you've been asking questions about me.
你知道我的名字
You know my name.
约翰
Johann.
[door closes]
从墨西哥入境 聪明 很聪明
Coming in through Mexico, smart. Very smart.
你怎么知道的 你是哪个部门的
How do you know this? What agency are you with?
他们说你杀了参议员
They say you killed a Senator.
他们认为你就是卡修斯
They think you're Cassius.
[whistles]
Uh-oh.
[chuckles]
你以为呢
What do you think?
你以为我会傻到用自己的手机打电话？
You think I'm stupid enough to callabcahead from my own phone?
你以为我在乎一个妓女的死活？
You think I give a damn what happens to some whore?
是的 我以前扮演过卡修斯
Yes. I've played Cassius before.
如果他们希望我是卡修斯 那我就是卡修斯
If they want me to be Cassius, I become Cassius.
可你不是
But you're not him.
是吗
Really?
你为何这么肯定
How can you be so sure?
因为我是卡修斯
Because I'm Cassius.
[shooting]
[groans]
[clap of thunder]
[siren blaring]
[muffled voices]
你当时在这里？
You were here?
是的
Yes, sir.
我立刻就跑到楼上
And I ran immediately upstairs.
[indistinct radio]
[dialing]
[telephone ringing]
喂 奥利 你追捕过Moussali吧
Hey. OIIie. Come on. You did the workabcon the Moussali capture, right?
用理论地理学查过他的行踪？
Applied some Iike theoretical geographyabcto his whereabouts?
是的 追踪一名逃犯
Yeah, that's right. Tracking a fugitive...
和追踪濒危物种差不多
is essentially the same thing as trackingabcan endangered species.
排除其不可能去的地方
You rule out the places they can't or won't go...
缩小到一些特定区域
until you have a reasonably few places to Iook.
用你的理论调查这个案子吧 来
You want in on this thing? Come on.
我要找什么
So, what is it I'm Iooking for?
卡修斯后期的作案 杀的不只是亲苏联的人
Late in Cassius' career, his murdersabcwere no longer just pro-Soviet.
也杀俄国人
He was killing Russians, too.
还有英国的 波兰的 捷克的 很多国家
And also English, Polish, Czech, you name it.
这是什么时候的？
When was this?
大约1988年
Around 1988.
让人百思不得其解
It never made any sense.
我好像遗漏了什么
I think I missed something here.
你为何觉得遗漏了什么
Why do you think you missed something?
你有什么新线索？
You have some new information?
保罗・谢泼德森
Paul Shepherdson.
怎么了
Yeah?
什么
What?
他在中情局干了25年
He's been at the company for Iike 25 years!
我知道 所以才需要你调查
Yeah, I know, man. That's whyabcI need you on this. Okay?
这些案卷我看过上千次了
I've been over this shit Iike a thousand times...
熟悉的都看不出什么异常了
to the point at which I alwaysabcsee the exact same thing.
你找出异常之处
Find something different.
好的 好
Okay. Yeah, sure. I--
如果你是对的 这意味着这么多年来
But if you're right, I mean, thatabcmeans the entire time...
他一直在追踪自己？
he's been hunting himself?
那么是他杀了参议员？
So, he killed the Senator?
如果我们判断正确的话
If we're right about this, yeah.
[telephone rings]
我是吉尔利特工
Agent Geary.
有个案卷我有个疑问
I've got a question about a file here.
是蓝色的案卷 夹着一张纸条 写着：
It's blue and it's got a note attached that says...
"太多的疑点 不可能是卡修斯"
"Too many questions. Not Cassius."
那个案子是恶作剧
Uh, No. That one's a hoax.
是拙劣的模仿卡修斯的手法
It's like a crude copycat murder.
那好 我就排除它
Okay, cool. I'll exclude it.
[squeaking]
我去买咖啡 替你捎点什么吗
I'm gonna run for coffee. Want something?
不用了 谢谢
Oh, no. I'm fine, thank you.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[soft music]
[grunts]
噢
Ooh.
天
Jesus!
保罗 嗨 谢谢你
Paul! Hi! Thank you!
你要小心点
You need to be careful.
我来
Yeah. Oh, Iet me--
别下来
Stay up there. [clears throat]
好
Okay.
我希望你让你丈夫申请退出这个案子
I want you to tell your husband to ask off this case.
让他说 这会给他本人和家庭带来危险
Have him say that it's just tooabcmuch for him, for his family.
不管是什么理由 只要让他退出
What-whatever he has to say, just get him out.
保罗 我能有什么办法
Paul, what do you expect me to do?
我说过 我不能再照看他了
You know, I told you. I can't watch over him anymore.
他已经很接近一个凶残的人
He's getting very close to a dangerous man.
他不会听我的
He won't Iisten to me.
我说什么他都不会听
He won't Iisten to anything I have to say, so--
他会死的 娜塔莉
He's gonna die, Natalie!
什么
What?
你明白了吗
Do you hear me now?
卡修斯曾经杀过
Cassius has taken out men...
比吉尔利老练的多的人
much more experienced than Ben.
对你和你的家人不会有丝毫怜悯之心
He doesn't give a damn about you, about your family.
他会杀了你丈夫
He will kill your husband.
不费吹灰之力
Like snapping his fingers.
不会有丝毫内疚
And he will feel nothing.
我把他每次作案的照片按照时间顺序排列起来
I pieced together the photos of every murderabcand I laid them out chronologically.
这条红线之后
Oh, that red Iine right there indicates...
他的作案就变得没有规律 难以解释了
where his killing became erratic and inexplicable.
你只要设立一个虚假设 然后去证明
So, all you've gotta do is set up a nullabchypothesis and try and prove it.
如果要证明不了 这说明你最初的假设肯定是对的
And when you can't prove it, that meansabcyour original hypothesis must be true.
不明白
Wait, wait.
举例来说
Take some fact.
你说过你认为卡修斯会回到犯罪现场
You said you believe Cassius returnsabcto the scene of the crimes.
你有每次作案的照片
And you've got photos of every murder.
比如你假设霍金就是卡修斯
So set up a hypothesis of, say,abcStephen Hawking is Cassius...
那么同时也就有霍金不是卡修斯的虚假设
which gives you a null hypothesis ofabcStephen Hawking is not Cassius.
你通过照片证明这个虚假设
So, go through the photos and try and prove the null...
"滚雷"不是卡修斯
that Rolling Thunder is not Cassius.
如果你能证明 说明你的假设是错的 如果不能
If you can, that means your hypothesisabcis incorrect. If you can't...
那么根据你的P值
then depending on your "P" value of course...
就能从统计学上证明你的假设肯定是对的
you've statistically proven yourabchypothesis must be true.
或者霍金就是卡修斯
Or that Stephen Hawking is Cassius.
是啊
Yeah.
不是每个人都在逻辑统计学课上睡觉的
Some of us didn't sleep our way throughabcLogic and Stats at Harvard.
这杯咖啡真管用
Damn, this coffee really works.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
保罗不是卡修斯
保罗是卡修斯
天啊
Jesus Christ.
嗨
[whispers] Hey.
Hey.
过来 小家伙
Hey. Come here, big guy.
他想爸爸了
He misses his daddy.
是吗
Yeah?
怎么了 老公
Sweetie, what is it?
没什么 你知道我很在乎你们吧
No, just, you know how muchabcI care about you guys, right?
天 我当然知道
Oh, God. Yeah. I do.
本
Ben?
我...
I just--
我来告诉你我要工作一个通宵
I-I just came home to tell youabcI've got to pull an all-nighter.
案子很快就结束的
It's all gonna be over soon.
是啊
Yeah.
本
Ben.
什么
Yeah?
保罗对我说
You know, Paul told me--
保罗？你们什么时候谈过
Paul? When were you talking to Paul?
他今天到书店 告诉我这个案子多危险
Well, he came by the store today andabche told me how dangerous this all is.
老婆 他的话一句也不要听
Honey. Don't Iisten to a word that that guy says, okay?
他就是个以为冷战仍在继续的老头
He's just an old man who thinksabcthat the war is still cold.
相信我 案子很快就会结束的
Trust me. This is all gonna be over soon.
你保证？
You promise?
是的 我该走了
Yeah. But I-I gotta go.
娜塔莉
Natalie?
算了
It's-- Never mind.
我按照你说的 深入调查了波兹洛斯基的一生
I dug deeper into Bozlovski's Iife Iike you asked.
这个人就是个杀人机器 随时随地
The guy's nothing but a killingabcmachine. Anywhere. Anytime.
他使用任何武器
He's used every single weapon you can think of...
从M-24坦克到生锈的钉子
from an M-24 from 800 meters to a rusty nail.
1988年6月他在哪儿
Where was he June 1988?
我们派他去了日内瓦 化名泰德・奥莱利
We had him flying into Geneva asabcan Irishman named Ted O'Leary.
在那里呆了四天
He was there for four days.
你在哪儿 你在哪儿
Where are you?
天
Holy shit.
波兹洛斯基？
Bozlovski?
[siren blaring]
我们要见面谈谈你的错误
不见面
什么错误
日内瓦的一个女人和孩子 你知道规矩
Hm.
天啊
Oh, my God.
波兹洛斯基杀了你家人
Bozlovski killed your family.
原来这么多年
So, all this time...
你是为了报仇
you were Iooking for revenge.
[telephone rings]
吉尔利特工
Agent Geary.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
我在挡风玻璃上告诉你了
You got my message on your windshield.
我知道真相
I know the truth.
你找了卡修斯很多年了吧
You've been Iooking for Cassiusabca Iong time, haven't you?
是的 现在我找到他了
Yeah. And now I've found him.
似乎是这样
It would seem so.
保罗・谢泼德森在哪儿
Where is Paul Shepherdson?
你想继续你的生意
Hey! You wanna keep your business your business?
还是想让警察都追捕你？
Or do you want every Fed in theabcDistrict down here up your ass?
快说 他在哪儿
So, goddammit, Where is he?
可以了
Good to go.
好 打开
All right, open it up!
[shooting]
怎么回事
What happened?
开门 快开门 快
Open the gate! Open the goddamn gate! Now!
快
Come on!
[groans]
[gunshots]
我为何没注意 保罗？
How did I miss it, Paul?
我为何没注意？
How did I miss it?
这么长时间 卡修斯就在我身边
The entire time, Cassius was right next to me!
把枪放下 吉尔利
Put the gun down, Geary!
难道我现在还能信任你吗
What? I'm supposed to trust you now?
好 我们谈谈信任
Yeah. Let's talk about trust.
第五列 卡修斯
Five down! Cassius.
第70行 Yepatb
Seventy across. Yepatb!
意思是"除掉"
Eliminated.
第32列 Bolxoh
Thirty-two down. Bolxoh.
意思是''出口"
Exit.
这是30年以前的苏联密码
This is 30-year-old Soviet code.
你家搬到这里的时候你有多大？
So, how old were you when-whenabcyour family came over here?
你也就十岁吧
What were you, about ten? Ten?
你只能做个间谍吧？
You never had a choice, did you?
你写了一篇论文 引起重视
So then you wrote a thesis that couldn't be ignored.
于是联邦调查局就找到你 录用了你
The FBI came after you. They signed you up.
你甚至为此成了家 真正的家庭
You even started a family. You started a real family!
来掩人耳目
To make it stick.
你就是个双面人
You've been a double your whole Iife.
他们什么时候让你开始行动的？
一年以前
让我为新来的人扫清道路
你割破参议员的喉咙 因为你知道你是专家
You cut the Senator's neck becauseabcyou knew you were the expert...
能让美国人相信是卡修斯干的
who could convince the Americansabcit was Cassius who did it.
然后把卡修斯调查出来
An investigation would flush Cassius out.
我收到的命令是杀了你
My orders are to kill you...
然后回到莫斯科
and return to Moscow.
我坐今晚的航班走
My plane Ieaves tonight.
一个人走？
Alone?
那你会一直是这样的人
Then that's all you'll ever be.
卡修斯
Cassius.
卡修斯正在逃走
Cassius is getting away.
喂 听我说
Hey, Iisten to me.
他受伤了 他无路可逃
He's wounded. He's cornered.
他不会交代 不会乖乖的
He's not gonna talk. He's not gonna play fair.
不会抓到活的
He's not gonna be taken alive.
对
Right.
吉尔利
Geary!
[exhales]
[grunts]
[groans]
别这样
Come on.
保罗？
Paul?
该死
Fuck.
回家吧
Go home.
你走吧
[whispers] You go--
[exhales]
[siren blaring]
查查卡修斯的手表
Check Cassius' watch.
拉开旋钮
Pull the knob.
他就是这么干的
That's how he did it.
这正是刀口的模式
Explains the cut pattern.
是波兹洛斯基的喉咙被割开了
Bozlovski's the one with the slit throat.
我听到一声枪声
I heard a shot.
转身的时候 就看见保罗倒下了
And when I turned around, I saw Paul going down.
不过是在他用卡修斯的金属丝勒死他以后
But not before he'd gotten Cassius'abcown wire around his neck.
卡修斯对保罗开的枪？
Cassius shot Paul?
研究弹道可以证明
The ballistics will prove it.
不过是在保罗抓住他以后
But not before Paul finally got his man.
是的
That's right.
干得好 吉尔利特工
Well done, Agent Geary.
你们要检查一下这条船
You might wanna check on that ship.
卡修斯来这里必有原因
Cassius was here for a reason.
这是什么
(Bell) What's this?
这是从船上掉下来的
These came off the boat, sir.
来
Ben!
告诉我
Tell me something.
你有没有考虑过为我们效力？
Would you ever consider working for us?
打扰一下 长官
(man) Excuse me, sir?
考虑一下
Think about it.
[Alex Lifeson sings Don't Look Back]